{
    "id": "32d3b00a39ce40bdac055c1e4f48bb36",
    "title": "Conditional Clauses Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "If I find your wallet, I ………………………… it to you.",
            "description": "In the first conditional, use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will/can/may + first form of the verb in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "will send",
                "would send",
                "would have sent"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "473c24fcb1404f299ba466e3ef298fe5"
        },
        {
            "question": "If she …………………… her lessons diligently, she would get a much better score.",
            "description": "In the second conditional, use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would/could/might + first form of the verb in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "learns",
                "learned",
                "had learned"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "6ebb375d90e74006ae7de0cbfc7718af"
        },
        {
            "question": "If she …………………….. your true identity, you will be in trouble.",
            "description": "In the first conditional, use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will/can/may + first form of the verb in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "discovers",
                "discovered",
                "had discovered"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "e6cdf28cc9e3462aa38d24e8c9b2cb9f"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you aren’t busy today, we …………………….. for a drive.",
            "description": "In the first conditional, use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will/can/may + first form of the verb in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "can go",
                "could go",
                "could have gone"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "9c11f0594b984b218c67793a06a6742f"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you don’t quit smoking, you ………………………….. cancer.",
            "description": "In the first conditional, use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will/can/may + first form of the verb in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "will have",
                "would have",
                "have"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "940be7b8756d47098ecc85717ebf02f1"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you had sent the money in the morning, she …………………………….. it in the evening.",
            "description": "In the third conditional, use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would/could/might + have + past participle in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "will receive",
                "would receive",
                "would have received"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "3305cd4955364e609af6baf172f712a9"
        },
        {
            "question": "If I had gone to university, I ………………………….. journalism.",
            "description": "In the third conditional, use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would/could/might + have + past participle in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "will study",
                "would study",
                "would have studied"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "7d16e6aa836149498a4b9048670bdc0e"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you had been more careful, you ……………………………… this mistake.",
            "description": "In the third conditional, use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would/could/might + have + past participle in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "will not make",
                "would not make",
                "would not have made"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "b1f409d846764f9bbc67c56cbc97c318"
        },
        {
            "question": "If I had heard the forecast, I ………………………….. an umbrella with me.",
            "description": "In the third conditional, use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would/could/might + have + past participle in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "will carry",
                "would carry",
                "would have carried"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "6878d3802eff4005932c7db13d2eaecb"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you started earlier, you …………………………. the bus.",
            "description": "In the second conditional, use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would/could/might + first form of the verb in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "will not miss",
                "would not miss",
                "would not have missed"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "9368045fd51f44e8ab984c4bf58f93db"
        },
        {
            "question": "If I ……………………….. guests, I will cook something delicious for them.",
            "description": "In the first conditional, use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will/can/may + first form of the verb in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "have",
                "had",
                "have had"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "dd256100269a4254b7dacbc30a4dad92"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you had waited, you ………………………….. a better offer.",
            "description": "In the third conditional, use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would/could/might + have + past participle in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "will receive",
                "would receive",
                "would have received"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "ca73e70bdffd47868faca2cf86f4c269"
        }
    ]
}